Good afternoon, everyone,
大家下午好，
thank you all for joining today,
感谢大家今天的参与，
my name is Alexander Amini
我的名字是 Alexander Amini，
and I'll be one of your course organizers this year
我将是你们今年的课程组织者之一，
along with Ava
和 Ava 一起，
and together we're super excited to
我们非常兴奋地
introduce you all to Introduction to Deep Learning,
向你们所有人介绍深度学习导论，
now MIT Introduction to Deep Learning is
MIT 的深度学习导论是
a really, really fun, exciting and fast paced program here at MIT
一个非常有趣、令人兴奋和快节奏的项目，
and let me start by just first of all, giving you a little bit of background
让我首先给你们一点背景，
into what we do and what you're going to learn about this year.
让你们了解我们今年所做的工作和你们将学到的东西。
So this week of Introduction to Deep Learning,
所以，本周的深度学习导论，
we're going to cover a ton of material in just one week,
我们将涉及大量的材料，在短短一周内，
you'll learn the foundations of this really, really fascinating and exciting field
你将学习这个非常吸引人和令人兴奋的领域的基础知识，
of deep learning and artificial intelligence
关于深度学习和人工智能，
and more importantly, you're going to get hands on experience,
更重要的是，你将亲身体验，
actually reinforcing what you learn in the lectures
巩固了你在课程中学到的内容，
as part of hands on software labs.
作为动手软件实验的一部分。
Now, over the past decade,
现在，在过去的十年里，
AI and deep learning have really had a huge resurgence
人工智能和深度学习有了巨大的复兴，
and had incredible successes
取得了令人难以置信的成功，
and a lot of problems, that even just a decade ago,
许多问题，即使在十年前，
we thought were not really even solvable in the near future,
我们还认为这些问题在不久的将来甚至无法真正解决，
now, we're solving with deep learning with incredible ease.
现在，我们用深度学习很轻松地解决。
Now, this past year in particular of 2022
在过去的这一年，尤其是 2022 年，
has been an incredible year for deep learning progress,
对于深度学习的进步来说，是令人难以置信的一年，
and I'd like to say,
我想说的是，
that actually this past year in particular has been the year of Generative Deep Learning,
过去的一年成为生成式深度学习的一年，
using deep learning to generate brand new types of data,
使用深度学习来生成全新类型的数据，
that I've never been seen before
我以前从未见过，
and never existed in reality.
在现实中也从未存在。
In fact I want to start this class
事实上，我想开始这门课，
by actually showing you how we started this class several years ago,
通过展示几年前我们是如何开始这门课的，
which was by playing this video, that I'll play in a second,
我马上会播放这段视频，
now, this video actually was an introductory video for the class,
这段视频实际上是这门课的介绍性视频，
it was and kind of exemplifies this idea that I'm talking about.
在某种程度上证明了我所说的想法。
So let me just stop there and play this video first of all.
所以，让我先停下来，播放这段视频。
Hi, everybody, and welcome to MIT 6.S191,
大家好，欢迎来到 MIT 6.S191 ，
the official introductory course on deep learning, taught here at MIT,
MIT 关于深度学习的官方入门课程，
deep learning is revolutionizing so many fields,
深度学习彻底改变了很多领域，
from robotics to medicine and everything in between,
从机器人到医学，以及介于两者之间的一切，
you'll learn the fundamentals of this field
你将学习这个领域的基础知识，
and how you can build some of these incredible algorithms,
以及如何构建一些令人难以置信的算法，
in fact, this entire speech and video are not real,
事实上，这个演讲和视频都不是真的，
and were created using deep learning and artificial intelligence,
是使用深度学习和人工智能创建的，
and in this class, you'll learn how,
在这节课上，你将学习如何，
it has been an honor to speak with you today,
今天很荣幸能和你们交谈，
and I hope you enjoy the course.
我希望你们喜欢这门课。
So in case you couldn't tell,
所以，为了防止你不能区分，
this video and its entire audio was actually not real,
这个视频和它的整个音频都不是真的，
it was synthetically generated by a deep learning algorithm,
它是由深度学习算法综合生成的，
and when we introduced this class a few years ago,
当我们几年前介绍这个课程的时候，
this video was created several years ago,
这个视频是几年前制作的，
but even several years ago,
但即使在几年前，
when we introduced this and put it on Youtube, went somewhat viral, right,
当我们将其放到 YouTube 上时，像病毒一样传播开来，
people really loved this video,
人们很喜欢这段视频，
they were intrigued by how real the video and audio felt and looked
他们对视频和音频的感觉的真实性很感兴趣，
entirely generated by an algorithm by a computer,
完全是由计算机通过算法生成的，
and people were shocked with the power and the realism of these types of approaches,
人们被这些方法的力量和现实主义所震惊，
and this was a few years ago.
这是几年前的事了。
Now, fast forward to today and the state of deep learning today,
现在，快进到今天，深度学习今天的状态，
we have, have seen deep learning accelerating at a rate faster than we've ever seen before,
我们已经看到深度学习以前所未有的速度加速，
in fact, we can use deep learning now to generate not just images of faces,
事实上，我们现在不仅可以使用深度学习来生成人脸图像，
but generate full synthetic environments,
还可以生成完全合成的环境，
where we can train autonomous vehicles entirely in simulation
我们可以完全在模拟中训练自动驾驶车辆，
and deploy them on full scale vehicles in the real world seamlessly,
并将它们无缝地部署在真实世界的全尺寸车辆上，
the videos here you see are actually from a data driven simulator,
你在这里看到的视频实际上是来自一个数据驱动的模拟器，
from neural networks generated called VISTA, that we actually built here at MIT
来自名为 VISTA 神经网络生成的，是我们在 MIT 建造的，
and have open source to the public,
并向公众开放了源代码，
so all of you can actually train and build the future of autonomy and self driving cars.
所以，你们所有人都可以训练和构建自动驾驶汽车的未来。
And of course it goes far beyond this as well,
当然，它也远远超出了这一点，
deep learning can be used to generate content directly from how we speak
深度学习可以直接从我们所说的话生成内容，
and the language that we convey to it, from prompts that we say,
我们传达给它的语言，我们说的提示，
deep learning can reason about the prompts in natural language, in English, for example,
深度学习可以对自然语言中的提示进行推理，比如英语，
and then guide and control what is generated according to what we specify,
然后根据我们指定的内容，指导和控制生成什么，
we've seen examples of where we can generate,
我们已经看到了我们可以生成的例子，
for example, things that again have never existed in reality,
例如，在现实中从未有过的东西，
we can ask a neural network to generate a photo of an astronaut riding a horse
我们可以让神经网络生成一张宇航员骑马的照片，
and it actually can imagine hallucinate what this might look like,
它可以想象这会是什么样子，
even though of course this photo,
即使这张照片，
not only this photo has never occurred before,
不仅这张照片以前从未发生过，
but I don't think any photo of an astronaut riding a horse has ever occurred before,
而且我认为以前没有发生过宇航员骑马的照片，
so there's not really even training data that you could go off in this case,
所以，在这种情况下，甚至没有训练数据可供参考，
and my personal favorite is actually,
我个人最喜欢的是，
how we can not only build software that can generate images and videos,
我们如何不仅可以构建能够生成图像和视频的软件，
but build software that can generate software as well,
而且还可以构建能够生成软件的软件，
we can also have algorithms that can take language prompts,
我们也可以有能够接受语言提示的算法，
for example a prompt like this,
例如，像这样的提示，
write code in Tensorflow to generate or to train a neural network,
在 TensorFlow 中编写代码来生成或训练神经网络，
and not only will it write the code and create that neural network,
它不仅会编写代码并创建神经网络，
but it will have the ability to reason about the code that it's generated
而且它还会有能力对它生成的代码进行推理，
and walk you through step by step explaining the process and procedure
并一步步地向你解释过程和程序，
all the way from the ground up to you,
从头到尾，
so that you can actually learn how to do this process as well.
这样你也可以学习如何完成这一过程。
Now, I think some of these examples
我认为这些例子中的一些
really just highlight how far deep learning and these methods have come,
确实突显了深度学习和这些方法，
in the past six years since we started this course,
在我们开始这门课程的过去六年里，
and you saw that example just a few years ago from that introductory video,
你在几年前的介绍性视频中看到了这个例子，
but now we're seeing such incredible advances,
但现在我们看到了如此令人难以置信的进步，
and the most amazing part of this course, in my opinion, is actually
在我看来，这门课程最令人惊叹的部分是，
that within this one week, we're going to take you through from the ground up, starting from today,
在这一周内，我们将从头开始，从今天开始，
all of that foundational building blocks,
所有的基础构件，
that will allow you to understand and make all of this amazing advances possible.
将让你理解，并使所有这些令人惊叹的进步成为可能。
So with that, hopefully now you're all super excited about what this class will teach,
有了这些，希望你们现在对这门课所教的内容感到很兴奋，
and I want to basically now just start by taking a step back
我想现在从退后一步开始，
and introducing some of these terminologies,
介绍一些术语，
that I've kind of been throwing around so far,
到目前为止我抛出的，
with deep learning, artificial intelligence,
深度学习，人工智能，
what do these things actually mean.
这些东西是什么意思。
So first of all, I want to maybe just take a second to,
所以首先，我想花点时间，
speak a little bit about intelligence
说一下智能，
and what intelligence means at its core.
以及智能的核心含义。
So to me, intelligence is simply the ability to process information,
对我来说，智能是一种处理信息的能力，
such that we can use it to inform some future decision or action that we take,
这样我们就可以用它来指导我们未来的决定或采取的行动，
now, the field of artificial intelligence is simply the ability for us to build algorithms,
现在，人工智能领域就是我们构建算法的能力，
artificial algorithms that can do exactly this,
人工算法，可以完成这个，
process information, to inform some future decision.
处理信息，指导未来的决策。
Now, machine learning is simply a subset of AI,
机器学习是人工智能的一个子集，
which focuses specifically on,
它特别关注，
how we can build a machine to or teach a machine,
我们如何构建一台机器或教一台机器，
how to do this from some experiences or data, for example.
如何根据一些经验或数据来做到这一点。
Now, deep learning goes one step beyond this
现在，深度学习更进一步，
and is a subset of machine learning,
它是机器学习的一个子集，
which focuses explicitly on what are called neural networks
它明确地关注所谓的神经网络，
and how we can build neural networks,
以及我们如何构建神经网络，
that can extract features in the data,
可以从数据中提取特征，
these are basically what you can think of as patterns, that occur within the data,
这些你可以认为是在数据中出现的模式，
so that it can learn to complete these tasks as well.
这样它也可以学习完成这些任务。
Now that's exactly what this class is really all about at its core,
这就是这门课核心的真正意义所在，
we're going to try and teach you
我们将尝试教你，
and give you the foundational understanding
给你基本的理解，
and how we can build and teach computers to learn tasks,
我们如何建立和教计算机学习任务，
many different types of tasks,
许多不同类型的任务，
directly from raw data,
直接从原始数据，
and that's really what this class boils down to at its most simple form.
这就是这门课最简单的形式。
And we'll provide a very solid foundation for you
我们将为你提供一个非常坚实的基础，
both on the technical side, through the lectures,
通过课程在技术方面，
which will happen in two parts throughout the class,
整个课程分两部分进行，
the first lecture and the second lecture,
第一节课，第二节课，
each one about one hour long,
每节课大约一个小时，
followed by a software lab,
随后是软件实验，
which will immediately follow the lectures,
紧跟在课程之后，
which will try to reinforce
它将试图加强，
a lot of what we cover in the in the technical part of the class,
很多我们在课程的技术部分中所涉及的内容，
and you know give you hands on experience implementing those ideas.
给你实践这些想法的经验。
So this program is split between these two pieces,
所以这个项目分为两部分，
the technical lectures and the software labs,
技术课程和软件实验，
we have several new updates this year in specific,
我们今年有几个具体的新更新，
especially in many of the later lectures.
特别是在后面的许多课程中。
The first lecture will cover the foundations of deep learning,
第一节课将涉及深度学习的基础，
which is going to be right now.
这是现在将要进行的。
And finally, we'll conclude the course
最后，我们将结束这门课程，
with some very exciting guest lectures from both academia and industry,
一些非常令人兴奋来自学术界和产业界的客座演讲，
who are really leading and driving forward the state of AI and deep learning,
他们真正引领和推动了人工智能和深度学习的发展。
And of course, we have many awesome prizes,
当然，我们还有很多令人惊叹的奖品，
that go with all of the software labs
这些奖品来自所有的软件实验，
and the project competition at the end of the course,
和课程结束时的项目竞赛，
so maybe quickly to go through these each day,
所以，也许每天要快速地经历这些，
like I said, we'll have dedicated software labs that couple with the lectures,
就像我说的，我们会有专门的软件实验，与课程相结合，
starting today, with lab one,
从今天开始，从实验一开始，
you'll actually build a neural network,
你将建立一个神经网络，
keeping with the theme of generative AI,
遵循生成性人工智能的主题，
you'll build a neural network,
你将构建一个神经网络，
that can learn, listen to a lot of music,
它可以学习、听很多音乐，
and actually learn how to generate brand new songs in that genre of music.
并学习如何在该音乐流派中生成全新的歌曲。
At the end, at the next level of the class, on Friday,
最后，在课程的下一阶段，在星期五，
we'll host a project pitch competition,
我们将举办一场项目推介比赛，
where either you individually or as part of a group
你可以单独或作为小组一员，
can participate and present an idea,
参与并向我们所有人展示一个想法，
a novel deep learning idea to all of us,
一个新颖的深度学习想法，
it will be roughly three minutes in length
这大约是三分钟的时间，
and we will focus not as much
我们不会关注太多，
because this is a one week program,
因为这是一个一周的计划，
we are not going to focus so much on the results of your pitch,
我们不会太关注你推介的结果，
but rather the innovation and the idea and the novelty of what you're trying to propose.
而是（关注）你试图提出的东西的创新、想法和新颖性。
The prizes here are are quite significant already,
这里的奖品已经相当可观了，
where first prize is going to get an NVIDIA GPU,
一等奖将获得 NVIDIA GPU ，
which is really a key piece of hardware,
这是一个关键的硬件，
that is instrumental,
这是工具性的，
if you want to actually build a deep learning project
如果你想建立一个深度学习项目，
and train these neural networks,
并训练这些神经网络，
which can be very large and require a lot of compute,
这些神经网络可能非常大，需要大量的计算，
these prizes will give you the compute to do so.
这些奖品将给你这样做的计算。
And finally this year we'll be awarding a grand prize
最后，今年我们颁发一个大奖，
for labs two and three combined,
为第二和第三个实验，
which will occur on Tuesday and Wednesday,
将于周二和周三举行，
focused on, what I believe is
关注于，我认为是，
actually solving some of the most exciting problems in this field of deep learning
解决深度学习领域中一些最令人兴奋的问题，
and how, specifically, how we can build models that can be robust,
以及我们如何具体地建立模型，可以健壮，
not only accurate, but robust and trustworthy and safe,
不仅准确，而且健壮，值得信赖和安全，
when they're deployed as well,
当它们部署时，
and you'll actually get experience developing those types of solutions,
你将获得开发这些类型的解决方案的经验，
that can actually advance the state-of-the-art in AI.
这些可以促进 AI 中最先进的。
Now, all of these labs that I mentioned and competitions here
我提到的所有这些实验和竞赛，
are going to be due on Thursday night, at 11pm,
将在周四晚上 11 点截止，
right before the last day of class.
也就是最后一天上课前。
And we'll be helping you all along the way,
我们会一路帮你，
this, this prize or this competition in particular has very significant prizes,
这个奖品，特别是这个比赛有很好的奖品，
so I encourage all of you to really enter this prize
所以我鼓励你们获取奖品，
and try to, try to get a chance to win the prize.
努力有机会赢得奖品。
And of course, like I said, we're going to be helping you all along the way,
当然，就像我说的，我们会一直帮助你，
here many available resources throughout this class to help you achieve this,
在整个课程中提供了许多可用的资源来帮助你实现这一点，
please post a Piazza, if you have any questions,
如果你有任何问题，请发布 Piazza ，
and of course this program has an incredible team,
当然，这个项目有一个令人难以置信的团队，
that you can reach out to at any point,
你可以随时联系，
in case you have any issues or questions on the materials,
以防你对材料有任何问题或疑问，
myself and Ava will be your two main lectures,
我和 Ava 将是你们的两个主要讲课，
for the first part of the class,
在课程的第一部分中，
we'll also be hearing,
我们也会听到，
like I said, in the later part of the class,
就像我说的，在课程后面部分，
from some guest lectures,
从一些客座讲课中，
who will share some really cutting edge state-of-the-art development in deep learning.
他们将分享一些深度学习最先进的发展。
And of course I want to give a huge shout out
当然，我想要大声说出，
and thanks to all of our sponsors,
感谢我们所有的赞助商，
who without their support,
如果没有他们的支持，
this program wouldn't have been possible for yet again another year,
这个项目在另一年是不可能的，
so thank you all.
所以谢谢你们。
Okay, so now with that,
好的，那么现在，
let's really dive into the really fun stuff of today's lecture,
让我们深入到今天课程中真正有趣的部分，
which is, you know, the, the technical part,
也就是技术部分，
and I think, I want to start this part
我想开始这个部分，
by asking all of you and having yourselves ask,
通过问你们，让你们自己问，
you know, having you ask yourselves this question,
你们问自己这个问题，
of, you know, why are all of you here, first of all,
首先，为什么你们在这里，
why do you care about this topic in the first place.
你们为什么一开始就关心这个话题。
I think to answer this question,
我认为要回答这个问题，
we have to take a step back
我们必须退后一步，
and think about, you know, the history of machine learning
想想机器学习的历史，
and what machine learning is
机器学习是什么，
and what deep learning brings to the table on top of machine learning.
深度学习在机器学习的基础上带来了什么。
Now, traditional machine learning algorithms typically define
传统的机器学习算法通常定义了
what are called these set of features in the data,
数据中所谓的这些特征集，
you can think of these as certain patterns in the data
你可以将这些视为数据中的特定模式，
and then usually these features are hand engineered,
通常这些特征都是手工设计的，
so probably a human will come into the data set
所以，可能会有一个人进入数据集，
and with a lot of domain knowledge and experience
并拥有大量的领域知识和经验，
can try to uncover what these features might be,
可以尝试发现这些特征可能是什么，
now the key idea of deep learning,
现在深度学习的关键思想，
and this is really central to this class is that,
也是这门课的核心是，
instead of having a human define these features,
不是让人来定义这些特征，
what if we could have a machine look at all of this data
如果我们可以让机器查看所有这些数据，
and actually try to extract and uncover what are the core patterns in the data,
并尝试提取和发现数据中的核心模式，
so that it can use those, when it sees new data to make some decisions.
以便在看到新数据时可以使用这些模式来做出一些决策。
So for example, if we wanted to detect faces in an image,
例如，如果我们想要检测图像中的人脸，
a deep neural network algorithm might actually learn that,
深度神经网络算法可能会了解到，
in order to detect a face,
为了检测人脸，
it first has to detect things like edges in the image lines and edges,
它首先必须检测图像中的线和边等东西，
and when you combine those lines and edges,
当你组合这些线和边时，
you can actually create compositions of features like corners and curves,
你可以创建特征的组合，比如角和曲线，
which when you create, when you combine those,
当你创建，当你组合这些特征时，
you can create more high level features,
你可以创建更高层次的特征，
for example eyes and noses and ears,
例如眼睛、鼻子和耳朵，
and then those are the features that allow you to ultimately detect what you care about,
然后，这些特征让你最终能够检测到你关心的东西，
detecting which is the face,
检测出哪个是人脸，
but all of these come from what are called kind of a hierarchical learning of features
但所有这些都来自于所谓的功能分层学习，
and you can actually see some examples of these,
你可以看到一些这样的例子，
these are real features learned by a neural network
这些都是通过神经网络学习到的真实特征，
and how they're combined defines this progression of information.
它们的组合方式定义了这一信息进程。
But in fact, what I just described,
但事实上，正如我刚才所描述的，
this underlying and fundamental building block of neural networks and deep learning have actually existed for decades,
这种神经网络和深度学习的基础和基础构件已经存在了几十年，
now. why are we studying all of this now at today in this class
为什么我们现在在这门课中学习这个，
with all this great enthusiasm to learn this, right.
怀着如此巨大的热情学习这些。
Well, for one, there have been several key advances that have occurred in the past decade.
首先，在过去的十年里，已经取得了几项关键的进展。
Number one is that data is so much more pervasive than it has ever been before in our lifetimes,
第一，数据比我们生活中的任何时候都更加普遍，
these models are hungry for more data,
这些模型渴望更多的数据，
and we're living in the age of big data,
而我们生活在大数据时代，
more data is available to these models than ever before
这些模型比以往任何时候都有更多的数据可用，
and they thrive off of that.
它们也因此而蓬勃发展。
Secondly, these algorithms are massively parallelizable,
第二，这些算法是大规模可并行化的，
they require a lot of compute
它们需要大量的计算，
and we're also at a unique time in history,
我们也正处于历史上一个独特的时刻，
where we have the ability to train these extremely large scale algorithms and techniques,
我们有能力训练这些超大规模算法和技术，
that have existed for a very long time,
它们存在了很长时间，
but we can now train them,
但是我们现在可以训练它们了，
due to the hardware advances that have been made.
由于硬件方面的进步。
And finally, due to open source toolbox and software platforms, like TensorFlow for example,
最后，由于开源工具箱和软件平台，比如 TensorFlow ，
which all of you will get a lot of experience on in this class,
你们在这门课上都会学到很多经验，
training and building the code for these neural networks has never been easier,
训练和构建这些神经网络的代码从来没有像现在这样容易，
so that from the software point of view as well,
所以，从软件的角度来看，
there have been incredible advances to open source,
开源已经有了令人难以置信的进步，
you know, the underlying fundamentals of what you're going to learn.
你将学到的基本原理。
So let me start now with just building up from the ground up,
现在让我从基础开始构建，
the fundamental building block of every single neural network,
每个神经网络的基本构件，
that you're going to learn in this class,
你们会在课程中学到的，
and that's going to be just a single neuron,
这只是单个神经元，
and in neural network language,
在神经网络语言中，
a single neuron is called a perceptron.
单个神经元被称为感知器。
So what is a perceptron,
那么什么是感知器，
a perceptron is, like I said, a single neuron,
就像我说的，感知器是一个单一的神经元，
and it's actually, I'm going to say it's very, very simple idea,
我要说这是一个非常非常简单的想法，
so I want to make sure that everyone in the audience understands exactly what a perceptron is
我想确保观众中的每个人都准确地理解感知器是什么，
and how it works.
以及它是如何工作的。
So let's start by first defining a perceptron
让我们首先定义感知器，
as taking, as input a set of inputs, right,
将一组输入作为输入，
so on the left hand side,
所以在左手边，
you can see this perceptron takes m different inputs, 1 to m,
你可以看到这个感知器接受 m 个不同的输入， 1 到 m ，
these are the blue circles,
这些是蓝色的圆圈，
We're denoting these inputs as xs,
我们将这些输入表示为 xs ，
each of these numbers, each of these inputs, is then multiplied by a corresponding weight,
这些数字中的每一个，每个输入，乘以相应的权重，
which we can call w,
我们可以称之为 w ，
so x1 will be multiplied by w1,
所以 x1 将乘以 w1 ，
and we'll add the result of all of these multiplications together,
我们将所有这些乘法的结果加在一起，
now, we take that single number after the addition,
现在，我们取相加后的单个数字，
and we pass it through this nonlinear,
我们把它通过这个非线性的，
what we call a nonlinear activation function,
我们称之为非线性激活函数，
and that produces our final output of the perception,
这产生了我们感知器的最终输出，
which we can call it y.
我们可以称之为 y 。
Now, this is actually not entirely accurate of the picture of a perceptron,
现在，这实际上并不完全准确地描述感知器的图像，
there's one step that I forgot to mention here,
有一个步骤我忘了在这里提了，
so in addition to multiplying all of these inputs with their corresponding weights,
所以除了将所有这些输入与其相应的权重相乘，
we're also now going to add what's called a bias term,
我们现在还将添加所谓的偏置项，
here denoted as this w0,
这里表示为 w0 ，
which is just a scalar weight,
这只是一个标量权重，
and you can think of it coming with an input of just 1,
你可以想象它的输入是 1 ，
so that's going to allow the network to basically shift its nonlinear activation function,
所以这将允许网络改变它的非线性激活函数，
you know, non linearly as it sees its inputs.
当它看到它的输入时，是非线性的。
Now on the right hand side,
现在在右手边，
you can see this diagram mathematically formulated, right,
你可以看到这张图是以数学形式表述的，
as a single equation,
一个单独的方程，
we can now rewrite this linear, this equation with linear algebra terms of vectors and dot products, right,
我们现在可以用向量和点积的线性代数项重写这个线性方程，
so for example, we can define our entire inputs x1 to xm as large vector X, right,
例如，我们可以将整个输入 x1 到 xm 定义为大的向量 X ，
that large vector X can be multiplied by or take a dot, excuse me, matrix multiplied with our weights W,
大的向量 X 可以乘以或者矩阵乘以我们的权重 W ，
again, another vector of our weights w1 to wm,
同样， W 是权重的向量 w1 到 wm ，
taking their dot product,
取它们的点积，
not only multiplies them, but it also adds the resulting terms together,
不仅会使它们相乘，而且还会将得到的项相加，
adding a bias, like we said before,
像我们前面说过的那样，增加一个偏置，
and applying this non-linearity.
并应用这个非线性函数。
Now you might be wondering,
现在你可能想知道，
what is this non-linear function,
这个非线性函数是什么，
I've mentioned it a few times already,
我已经提过好几次了，
well, I said it is a function, right,
我说过这是一个函数，
that's that we pass the outputs of the neural network through
我们将神经网络的输出传给它，
before we return it, you know, to the next neuron in the, in the pipeline,
在返回给管道中的下一个神经元之前，
so one common example of a non-linear function,
所以一个非线性函数的常见例子，
that's very popular in deep neural networks,
在深度神经网络中非常流行的，
it's called the sigmoid function,
叫做 sigmoid 函数，
you can think of this as kind of a continuous version of a threshold function, right,
你可以把它看作是阈值函数的一种连续形式，
it goes from 0 to 1,
它从 0 到 1 ，
and it's having, it can take us, input any real number on the real number line,
它可以让我们在实数线上输入任何实数，
and you can see an example of it illustrated on the bottom right hand,
你可以在右下角看到一个例子，
now, in fact, there are many types of non-linear activation functions,
事实上，非线性激活函数有很多种，
that are popular in deep neural networks
在深度神经网络中流行的，
and here are some common ones,
下面是一些常见的，
and throughout this presentation,
在整个演示过程中，
you'll actually see some examples of these code snippets on the bottom of the slides,
你将在幻灯片底部看到这些代码片段的一些示例，
where we'll try and actually tie in some of what you're learning in the lectures
我们将尝试将你在课程中学到的一些内容
to actual software and how you can implement these pieces,
与实际软件以及你如何实现这些部分联系起来，
which will help you a lot for your software labs explicitly,
这将对你的软件实验有很大帮助，
so the sigmoid activation on the left is very popular,
所以左边的 sigmoid 激活函数非常流行，
since it's a function that outputs, you know, between 0 and 1,
因为它是一个输出在 0 到 1 之间的函数，
so especially when you want to deal with probabilities distributions, for example,
所以特别是当你想要处理概率分布时，
this is very important because probabilities live between 0 and 1,
这是非常重要的，因为概率在 0 到 1 之间，
in modern deep neural networks though, the ReLU function,
在现代深层神经网络中， ReLU 函数，
which you can see on the far right hand,
你可以在最右边看到，
is a very popular activation function,
是一个非常流行的激活函数，
because it's piece wise, linear,
因为它是分段的，线性的，
it's extremely efficient to compute,
所以它的计算非常高效，
especially when computing its derivatives,
特别是在计算它的导数时，
its derivatives are constants,
它的导数是常量，
except for one non-linear yet 0,
除了一个是非线性的， 0 。
Now I hope actually all of you are probably asking this question to yourself of
现在，我希望你们所有人都在问自己这个问题，
why do we even need this nonlinear activation function,
为什么我们需要这个非线性激活函数，
it seems like it kind of just complicates this whole picture,
它似乎让整个情况变得复杂起来，
when we didn't really need it in the first place,
当我们一开始并不需要它，
and I want to just spend a moment on answering this,
我想花一点时间来回答这个问题，
because the point of a non-linear activation function is
因为非线性激活函数的要点是，
of course, number one is to introduce non-linearities to our data, right,
当然，第一是引入数据的非线性，
if we think about our data,
如果我们考虑我们的数据，
almost all data that we care about,
几乎所有我们关心的数据，
all real world data is highly non-linear,
所有现实世界的数据都是高度非线性的，
now this is important,
这一点很重要，
because if we want to be able to deal with those types of datasets,
因为如果我们想要处理这些类型的数据集，
we need models that are also non-linear,
我们需要同样是非线性的模型，
so they can capture those same types of patterns,
这样它们才能捕捉到相同类型的模式，
so imagine I told you to separate,
想象一下我让你们分开，
for example, I gave you this dataset, red points and green points,
例如，我给你这个数据集，红点和绿点，
and I ask you to try and separate those two types of data points,
我请你试着区分这两种类型的数据点，
now you might think that this is easy,
现在你可能认为这很容易，
but if I could, only if I told you that you could only use a single line to do so,
但如果我告诉你，你只能用一条线来做到这一点，
well, now it becomes a very complicated problem,
那么现在它变成了一个非常复杂的问题，
in fact, you can't really solve it effectively with a single line,
事实上，你不可能用一条线有效地解决这个问题，
and in fact, if you introduce non-linear activation functions to your solution,
事实上，如果你在你的解决方案中引入非线性激活函数，
that's exactly what allows you to, you know, deal with these types of problems,
你就可以来处理这类问题，
non-linear activation functions allow you to deal with non-linear types of data.
非线性激活函数允许你处理非线性类型的数据。
Now, and that's what exactly makes neural networks so powerful at their core.
这正是神经网络的核心如此强大的原因。
So let's understand this maybe with a very simple example,
让我们通过一个非常简单的例子来理解这一点，
walking through this diagram of a perceptron one more time,
再看一下感知器的图示，
imagine I give you this trained neural network with weights,
想象一下，我给你这个训练有素的神经网络和权重，
now not w1 w2, I'm going to actually give you numbers at these locations,
现在不是 w1 w2 ，我要给你们这些位置的数字，
so the trained weights w0 will be 1
所以，训练后的 w0 是 1 ，
and W will be a vector of 3 and -2,
W 是向量 3 和 -2 ，
so, this neural network has two inputs,
所以，这个神经网络有两个输入，
like we said before, it has input x1, it has input x2,
就像我们之前说的，它有输入 x1 和 x2 ，
if we want to get the output of it,
如果我们想要得到它的输出，
this is also the main thing,
这也是主要内容，
I want all of you to take away from this lecture today
我希望你们从今天的演讲中学到的，
is that to get the output of a perceptron
为了得到感知器的输出，
and there are three steps we need to take,
我们需要采取三个步骤，
from this stage, we first compute the multiplication of our inputs with our weights,
在这个阶段，我们首先计算输入和权重的乘法，
sorry, yeah, multiply them together, add their result and compute non-linearity,
抱歉，是的，把它们相乘，结果相加，并计算非线性函数，
it's these three steps that define the forward propagation of information through a perceptron.
这三个步骤定义了信息通过感知器的前向传播。
So let's take a look at how that exactly works, right,
那么，让我们来看看它到底是如何工作的，
so if we plug in these numbers to to those equations,
所以如果我们把这些数字放入方程中，
we can see that everything inside of our non-linearity,
我们可以看到非线性函数里面的所有东西，
here the non-linearity is g, right,
这里非线性函数是 g ，
that function g which could be a sigmoid,
g 函数可能是 sigmoid ，
we saw in previous slide,
我们在之前的一张幻灯片看到，
that component inside our non-linearity is in fact just a two dimensional line,
事实上，我们的非线性函数中的那个分量只是一条二维线，
it has two inputs
它有两个输入，
and if we consider the space of all of the possible inputs that this neural network could see,
如果我们考虑这个神经网络可以看到的所有可能的输入的空间，
we can actually plot this on a decision boundary, right,
我们可以把它画在决策边界上，
we can plot this two dimensional line, as as a decision boundary,
我们可以画这条二维线，作为决定边界，
as a [plane] separating these two components of our space,
就像分隔我们空间的这两个组成部分的平面，
in fact not only is it a single plane,
事实上，它不仅是一个单一的平面，
there's a directionality component depending on which side of the plane that we live on,
还有一个方向性成分，取决于我们在平面的哪一边，
if we see an input, for example here, -1 2,
如果我们看到一个输入，例如这里的 -1 2 ，
we actually know that it lives on one side of the plane
我们知道它位于平面的一侧，
and it will have a certain type of output,
它会有某种类型的输出，
in this case, that output is going to be positive, right,
在这种情况下，输出将是正的，
because in this case, when we plug those components into our equation,
因为在这种情况下，当我们将这些分量放入我们的方程时，
we'll get a positive number, that passes through the non-linear component,
我们会得到一个正数，通过非线性分量，
and that gets propagated through as well,
它也会通过传播，
of course if you're on the other side of the space,
当然，如果你在空间的另一边，
you're going to have the opposite result, right,
你会得到相反的结果，
and that thresholding function is going to essentially live at this decision boundary,
这个阈值函数就在这个决策边界上，
so depending on which side of the space you live on,
所以，根据你所在空间的哪一边，
that thresholding function, that sigmoid function, is going to then control how you move to one side or the other.
阈值函数， sigmoid 函数将控制你移动到一边或另一边。
Now in this particular example, this is very convenient,
现在在这个特定的例子中，这是非常方便的，
because we can actually visualize,
因为我们可以可视化，
and I can draw this exact full space for you on this slide,
我可以在这张幻灯片上为你们画出这个完整的空间，
it's only a two dimensional space,
它只是一个二维空间，
so it's very easy for us to visualize,
所以我们很容易可视化，
but of course, for almost all problems that we care about,
但是当然，对于我们关心的几乎所有问题，
our data points are not going to be two dimensional,
我们的数据点都不会是二维的，
if you think about an image,
如果你考虑一幅图像，
the dimensionality of an image is going to be the number of pixels, that you have in the image,
图像的维度将是你在图像中拥有的像素数，
so these are going to be thousands of dimensions, millions of dimensions or even more,
所以这些将是数千个维度，数百万个维度，甚至更多，
and then drawing these types of plots like you see here is simply not feasible,
然后像你在这里看到的那样绘制这些类型的图是根本不可行的，
so we can't always do this,
所以我们不能总是这样做，
but hopefully this gives you some intuition
但希望这能给你一些直觉，
to understand kind of as we build up into more complex models.
来理解我们建立更复杂的模型。
So now that we have an idea of the perceptron,
现在我们已经对感知器有了一个概念，
let's see how we can actually take this single neuron
让我们看看我们如何真正地利用这个单一的神经元，
and start to build it up into something more complicated,
并开始将其构建成更复杂的东西，
a full neural network,
一个完整的神经网络，
and build a model from that.
并由此建立一个模型。
So let's revisit again this previous diagram of the perceptron,
所以让我们再来回顾一下之前的感知器示意图，
if, again just to reiterate one more time,
如果，我再重申一次，
this core piece of information,
这里的核心信息，
that I want all of you to take away from this class is
我想让你们所有人从这门课上学到的是，
how a perceptron works and
感知器是如何工作的，
how it propagates information to its decision,
以及它是如何将信息传播到决策中的，
there are three steps,
这里有三个步骤，
first is the dot product, second is the bias, and third is the non-linearity,
第一是点积，第二是偏置，第三是非线性，
and you keep repeating this process for every single perceptron in your neural network.
你对你神经网络中的每一个感知器都重复这个过程。
Let's simplify the diagram a little bit,
让我们稍微简化一下图表，
I'll get rid of the weights
我将去掉权重，
and you can assume that every line here now basically has an associated weight scalar, that's associated with it,
你可以假设这里的每一行都有一个关联的权重标量，
every line also corresponds to the input that's coming in,
每一行也对应于输入，
it has a weight that's coming in also at the, on the line itself,
它有一个权重输入在行上，
and I've also removed the bias just for sake of simplicity,
为了简单起见，我也去掉了偏置，
but it's still there,
但它仍然存在，
so now the result is that z,
现在结果是 z ，
which let's call that the result of our dot product plus the bias is going
我们称之为点积加上偏置的结果，
and that's what we pass into our non-linear function,
这就是我们传递给非线性函数的，
that piece is going to be applied to that activation function,
这一块将应用于激活函数，
now the final output here is simply going to be g,
现在，这里的最终输出将是 g ，
which is our activation function of z,
这是我们的 z 的激活函数，
z is going to be basically what you can think of the state of this neuron,
z 就是你可以认为这个神经元的状态，
it's the result of that dot product plus bias.
它是点积加上偏置的结果。
Now, if we want to define and build up a multi layered output neural network,
现在，如果我们想定义和建立一个多层输出神经网络，
if we want two outputs to this function, for example,
比如，如果我们想要这个函数的两个输出，
it's a very simple procedure,
这是一个非常简单的过程，
we just have now two neurons, two perceptons,
我们现在只有两个神经元，两个感知器，
each perceptron will control the output for its associated piece, right,
每个感知器将控制其相关部分的输出，
so now we have two outputs,
所以现在我们有两个输出，
each one is the normal perceptron,
每一个都是正常的感知器，
it takes all of the inputs,
它接受所有的输入，
so they both take the same inputs,
所以它们都接受相同的输入，
but amazingly,
但令人惊讶的是，
now with this mathematical understanding,
现在有了这样的数学理解，
we can start to build our first neural network entirely from scratch.
我们可以开始完全从头开始建立我们的第一个神经网络。
So what does that look like,
那么这是什么样子的呢，
so we can start by firstly initializing these two components,
我们可以首先初始化这两个组件，
The first component that we saw was the weight matrix, excuse me, the weight vector,
我们看到的第一个分量是权重矩阵，抱歉，是权重向量，
It's a vector of weights in this case,
在这种情况下，它是权重的向量，
and the second component is the, the bias vector,
第二个分量是偏置向量，
that we're going to multiply with the dot product of all of our inputs by our weights, right,
我们要乘以所有输入的点积乘以我们的权重，
so, the only remaining step now
所以，现在剩下的唯一一步，
after we've defined these parameters of our layer is to
在我们定义了层的这些参数之后，
now define, you know, how this forward propagation of information works,
定义信息的前向传播是如何工作的，
and that's exactly those three main components, that I've been stressing to you,
这正是我向你们强调的三个主要组成部分，
so we can create this call function to do exactly that,
所以我们可以创建这个 call 函数来实现这一点，
to define this forward propagation of information,
定义信息的正向传播，
and the story here is exactly the same as we've been seeing it, right,
这里的故事和我们一直看到的完全一样，
matrix, multiply our inputs with our weights,
矩阵，将我们的输入乘以我们的权重，
add a bias,
添加偏置，
and then apply a non-linearity
然后应用非线性函数，
and return the result
并返回结果，
and that literally this code will run,
这段代码就会运行，
this will define a full, a full neural network layer,
这将定义一个完整的神经网络层，
that you can then take like this,
然后你可以这样做，
and of course, actually, luckily for all of you,
当然，实际上，对你们所有人来说幸运的是，
all of that code, which wasn't much code,
所有的代码，不是很多代码，
that's been abstracted away by these libraries, like TensorFlow,
被这些库抽象出来，比如 TensorFlow ，
you can simply call functions like this,
你可以简单地像这样调用函数，
which will actually, you know, replicate exactly that piece of code,
它会复制这段代码，
so you don't need to necessarily copy all of that code down,
所以，你不必将所有代码都复制下来，
you can just call it.
你可以直接调用它。
And with that understanding,
有了这种理解，
you know, we just saw how you could build a single layer,
我们刚刚看到了如何建立一个单一的层，
but of course, now you can actually start to think about how you can stack these layers as well,
当然，现在你也可以开始考虑如何堆叠这些层了，
so since we now have this transformation essentially from our inputs to a hidden output,
既然我们现在有了从输入到隐藏输出的转换，
you can think of this as basically
你可以认为，
how we can define some way
我们如何定义一些方法，
of transforming those inputs, right, into some new dimensional space, right,
将这些输入直接转换到某个新的维度空间，
perhaps closer to the value that we want to predict,
也许更接近我们想要预测的值，
and,that -} transformation is going to be eventually learned
而这种转换最终将被学习，
to know how to transform those inputs into our desired outputs,
知道如何将这些输入转换为我们想要的输出，
and we'll get to that later,
我们稍后会讲到这一点，
but for now, the piece that I want to really focus on is,
但现在，我真正想要关注的是，
if we have these more complex neural networks,
如果我们有这些更复杂的神经网络，
I want to really distill down that,
我想真正地提炼出，
this is nothing more complex than what we've already seen,
这并不比我们已经看到的更复杂，
if we focus on just one neuron in this diagram,
如果我们只关注这张图中的一个神经元，
take here, for example, z2,
以这里的 z2 为例，
z2 is this neuron that's highlighted in the middle layer,
z2 是中间层突出显示的神经元，
it's just the same perceptron that we've been seeing so far in this class,
这就是我们到目前为止在这门课上看到的感知器，
it was, its output is
它的输出是
obtained by taking a dot product, adding a bias, and then applying that non-linearity between all of its inputs,
通过取一个点积，加上一个偏置，然后在所有输入之间应用非线性函数得到的，
if we look at a different node,
如果我们看一个不同的节点，
for example z3, which is the one right below it,
例如 z3 ，就在它的正下方，
it's the exact same story,
它是完全相同的故事，
again, it sees all the same inputs,
同样，它看到的是所有相同的输入，
but it has a different set of weight matrix,
但它有一组不同的权重矩阵，
that it's going to apply to those inputs,
将应用于这些输入，
so we'll have a different output,
所以我们会有不同的输出，
but the mathematical equations are exactly the same.
但数学方程是完全相同的。
So from now on,
所以从现在开始，
I'm just going to kind of simplify all of these lines and diagrams
我将简化所有这些线条和图表，
just to show these icons in the middle,
只是展示中间的这些图标，
just to demonstrate that these means,
只是为了证明，这些意味着，
everything is going to be fully connected to everything
一切都将完全与一切联系在一起，
and defined by those mathematical equations that we've been covering,
并由我们一直介绍的那些数学公式定义，
but there's no extra complexity in these models
但这些模型并没有额外的复杂性，
from what you've already seen.
从你已经看到的情况来看。
Now, if you want to stack these types of solutions on top of each other,
现在，如果你想把这些类型的解决方案叠加在一起，
these layers on top of each other,
这些层叠加在一起，
you can not only define one layer very easily,
你不仅可以非常容易地定义一个层，
but you can actually create what are called sequential models,
而且你可以创建所谓的顺序模型，
these sequential models, you can define one layer after another
这些顺序模型，你可以定义一个又一个层，
and they define basically the forward propagation of information,
它们定义了信息的正向传播，
not just from the neuron level, but now from the layer level,
不仅是从神经元层面，现在是从层层面，
every layer will be fully connected to the next layer,
每一层都将完全连接到下一层，
and the inputs of the secondary layer will be all of the outputs of the prior layer.
第二层的输入将是上一层的所有输出。
Now, of course, if you want to create a very deep neural network,
现在，当然，如果你想创建一个非常深入的神经网络，
all the deep neural network is,
所有的深层神经网络就是，
is we just keep stacking these layers on top of each other,
我们只是把这些层堆叠在一起，
there's nothing else to this story,
这个故事没有什么不同，
that's really as simple as it is,
和之前一样简单，
once, so these layers are basically all they are is just layers,
所以，这些层全部只是层，
where the final output is computed, right,
最终输出被计算，
by going deeper and deeper into this progression of different layers,
通过深入不同层的过程，
and you just keep stacking them,
你只是不断地堆叠它们，
until you get to the last layer, which is your output layer,
直到你到达最后一层，也就是你的输出层，
it's your final prediction that you want to output, right,
这是你想要输出的最终预测，
we can create a deep neural network to do all of this
我们可以创建一个深度神经网络来完成这一切，
by stacking these layers and creating these more hierarchical models,
通过堆叠这些层并创建这些更具层次感的模型，
like we saw very early in the beginning of today's lecture,
就像我们在今天课程开始时看到的那样，
one where the final output is really computed by,
最终输出被计算是通过，
you know, just going deeper and deeper into this system.
只是越来越深入地进入这个系统。
Okay, so that's awesome.
好的，这太棒了。
So we've now seen how we can go from a single neuron to a layer
我们现在已经看到了如何从单个神经元到一个层，
to all the way to a deep neural network
再到一个深层神经网络，
building off of these foundational principles.
建立在这些基本原理之上。
Let's take a look at how exactly we can use these, you know, principles,
让我们来看看我们如何使用这些原理，
that we've just discussed
我们刚刚讨论的，
to solve a very real problem,
来解决一个非常现实的问题，
that I think all of you are probably very concerned about this morning when you, when you woke up.
我想你们今天早上醒来时可能都非常关注这个问题。
So that problem is,
所以问题是，
how we can build a neural network to answer this question,
我们如何建立一个神经网络来回答这个问题，
which is will I, how will I pass this class,
我将如何通过这门课，
and if I will, will I not.
我能不能通过。
So to answer this question,
所以，为了回答这个问题，
let's see if we can train a neural network to solve this problem.
让我们看看是否可以训练一个神经网络来解决这个问题。
So to do this,
要做这个，
let's start with a very simple neural network,
让我们从一个非常简单的神经网络开始，
we'll train this model with two inputs,
我们将用两个输入训练这个模型，
just two inputs,
只有两个输入，
one input is going to be the number of lectures that you attend, over the course of this one week,
一个输入是你在这一周中参加的讲座的数量，
and the second input is going to be how many hours that you spend on your final project or your competition.
第二个输入将是你在期末项目或竞争中花费了多少小时。
Okay, so what we're going to do is,
好的，所以我们要做的是，
firstly go out and collect a lot of data
首先去收集大量数据，
from all of the past years that we've taught this course,
从过去几年我们教授这门课程中，
and we can plot all of this data,
我们可以绘制所有这些数据，
because it's only two input space,
因为它只有两个输入空间，
we can plot this data on a two dimensional feature space,
我们可以将这些数据绘制在二维特征空间上，
we can actually look at all of the students before you,
我们可以看看你们前面所有学生，
that have passed the class and failed the class
通过课程和不及格的，
and see where they lived in this space
看看他们在这个空间里在哪里，
for the amount of hours that they've spent,
他们花了多少个小时，
the number of lectures that they've attended,
听了多少节课，
and so on,
诸若此类，
green point are the people who have passed, red are those who have failed,
绿点是通过的人，红点是不及格的，
now, and here's you, right,
现在，这是你，
you're right here,
你在这里，
4 5 is your coordinate space,
4 5 是你的坐标空间，
you fall right there
你在那里，
and you've attended four lectures,
你已经听了四节课，
you've spent five hours on your final project,
你已经在期末作业上花了五个小时，
we want to build a neural network to answer the question
我们想建立一个神经网络来回答这样一个问题，
of will you pass the class or will you fail the class.
你会通过这门课还是不及格。
So let's do it,
那我们开始吧，
we have two inputs,
我们有两个输入，
one is four, one is five,
一个是 4 ，一个是 5 ，
these are two numbers,
这是两个数字，
we can feed them through a neural network,
我们可以把它们给神经网络，
that we've just seen how we can build that,
我们刚刚看到的如何构建的（神经网络），
and we feed that into a single layered neural network,
我们把它输入到一个单层神经网络中，
three hidden units in this example,
在这个例子中是三个隐藏的单元，
but we could make it larger,
但我们可以把它做得更大，
if we wanted to be more expressive and more powerful,
如果我们想要更有表现力和更强大，
and we see here that,
我们在这里看到，
the probability of you passing those classes is 0.1,
你通过这些课程的概率是 0.1 ，
pretty abysmal.
相当糟糕。
So why would this be the case, right,
那么为什么会出现这种情况，
what did we do wrong,
我们做错了什么，
because I don't think it's correct, right,
因为我不认为这是正确的，
when we looked at the space,
当我们看这个空间的时候，
it looked like actually you were a good candidate to pass the class,
看起来你是通过这门课的很好的候选人，
but why is the neural network saying that there's only a 10% likelihood that you should pass,
但是为什么神经网络说你通过考试的可能性只有 10% 呢，
does anyone have any ideas?
有谁有什么想法吗？
Exactly, exactly,
完全正确，
so, this neural network is just, like it was just born, right,
所以，这个神经网络它刚刚诞生，
it has no information about the world or this class,
它没有关于这个世界或这个课程的信息，
it doesn't know what 4 and 5 mean,
它不知道 4 和 5 是什么意思，
or what the notion of passing or failing means, right.
也不知道及格或不及格的概念是什么意思。
Exactly right,
完全正确，
this neural network has not been trained,
这个神经网络还没有经过训练，
you can think of it kind of as a baby,
你可以把它想象成一个婴儿，
it hasn't learned anything yet,
它还没有学到任何东西，
so our job firstly is to train it,
所以，我们的首要工作是训练它，
and part of that understanding is
这种理解的一部分是，
we first need to tell the neural network, when it makes mistakes,
当神经网络出错时，我们首先需要告诉它，
so mathematically we should now think about how we can answer this question,
所以，从数学上讲，我们现在应该考虑如何回答这个问题，
which is, did my neural network make a mistake,
即我的神经网络是否犯了错误，
and if it made a mistake,
如果它犯了一个错误，
how can I tell it how big of a mistake it was,
我如何告诉它这个错误有多大，
so that the next time it sees this data point,
以便它下一次看到这个数据点时，
can it do better, minimize that mistake.
可以做得更好，将错误降到最低。
So in neural network language,
所以，在神经网络语言中，
those mistakes are called losses,
这些错误被称为损失，
and specifically you want to define what's called a loss function,
具体来说，你想定义所谓的损失函数，
which is going to take as input your prediction and the true prediction, right,
它将把你的预测和真实的预测作为输入，
and how far away your prediction is from the true prediction
你的预测与真实预测的距离，
tells you how big of a loss there is, right,
告诉你有多大的损失，
so, for example,
比如，
let's say we want to build a neural network to do classification of,
比如，我们想要建立一个神经网络来进行分类，
or, sorry, actually, even before that, I want to maybe give you some terminology.
抱歉，在此之前，我想给你们一些术语，
So there are multiple different ways of saying the same thing,
有多种不同的方式来表达相同的事情，
in neural networks and deep learning,
在神经网络和深度学习中，
so what I just described as a loss function
所以我刚才描述的损失函数，
is also commonly referred to as an objective function, empirical risk, a cost function,
也通常被称为目标函数，经验风险，成本函数，
these are all exactly the same thing,
这些都是完全一样的东西，
they're all a way for us to train the neural network,
它们都是我们训练神经网络的一种方式，
to teach the neural network when it makes mistakes,
在神经网络出错时教它，
and what we really ultimately want to do is
我们最终真正想要做的是，
over the course of an entire data set,
在整个数据集的过程中，
not just one data point of mistakes,
而不仅是一个错误数据点，
we want to say over the entire data set,
我们想要在整个数据集上，
we want to minimize all of the mistakes on average that this neural network makes.
我们想要将这个神经网络犯下的所有平均错误降到最低。
So if we look at the problem, like I said, of binary classification,
所以，如果我们看二元分类问题，
will I pass this class or will I not,
我会通过这门课吗，
there's a yes or no answer,
这里有一个是或不是的答案，
that means binary classification,
这意味着二元分类，
now we can use what's called a loss function of the softmax cross entropy loss,
现在我们可以使用所谓的 softmax 交叉熵损失的损失函数，
and for those of you who aren't familiar,
对于你们中不熟悉的人来说，
this notion of cross entropy is actually developed here at MIT
交叉熵的概念是在 MIT 开发的，
by Shannon, excuse me, yes, Claude Shannon,
由 Claude Shannon ，
who is visionary,
他很有远见，
he did his masters here over fifty years ago,
五十多年前，他在这里攻读硕士学位，
he introduced this notion of cross entropy,
他引入了交叉熵的概念，
and that was, you know, pivotal and the ability for us to train these types of neural networks,
这就是我们有能力训练这些类型的神经网络的关键，
even now into the future.
即使是现在也是如此。
So let's start by,
所以，让我们开始，
instead of predicting a binary cross entropy output,
不是预测二元交叉熵输出，
what if we wanted to predict a final grade of your class score, for example,
例如，如果我们想要预测你班级成绩的最终分数，
that's no longer a binary output, yes or no,
这不再是一个二元输出，是或否，
it's actually a continuous variable, right,
它是一个连续变量，
it's the grade, let's say out of 100 points,
这是分数，满分是 100 分，
what is the value of your score in the class project,x
你在班级项目中的分数是多少，
for this type of loss, we can use what's called a mean squared error loss,
对于这种损失，我们可以使用所谓的均方误差损失，
you can think of this literally as
你可以从字面上认为，
just subtracting your predicted grade from the true grade
这只是从真实分数中减去你的预测分数，
and minimizing that distance apart.
并将两者之间的距离最小化。
So I think now we're ready to really put all of this information together
所以，我认为现在我们已经准备好将所有这些信息整合在一起，
and tackle this problem of training a neural network
解决这个训练神经网络，
to not just identify how erroneous it is,
不仅仅是识别它是多么错误，
how large its loss is,
它的损失有多大，
but more importantly, minimize that loss,
但更重要的是，将这种损失降至最低，
as a function of seeing all of this training data that it observes.
通过查看它观察到的所有这些训练数据。
So we know that we want to find this neural network,
所以我们想要找到这个神经网络，
like we mentioned before,
就像我们之前提到的那样，
that minimizes this empirical risk or this empirical loss averaged across our entire data set,
它可以最小化整个数据集的经验风险或经验损失的平均值，
now this means that we want to find mathematically these ws, right,
这意味着我们想要在数学上找到这些 w ，
that minimize J(W),
最小化 J(W) ，
J(W) is loss function averaged over our entire data set,
J(W) 是损失函数平均在整个数据集上，
and W is our weight,
W 是我们的权重，
so we want to find the set of weights,
所以我们想要找到一组权重，
that on average is going to give us the minimum, smallest loss as possible,
平均而言，它会给我们最小的损失，
now, remember that W here is just a list,
现在，记住 W 在这里只是一个列表，
basically, it's just a group of all of the weights in our neural network,
它只是我们神经网络中所有权重的一组，
you may have hundreds of weights and a very, very small neural network,
你可能有数百个权重和一个非常小的神经网络，
or in today's neural networks, you may have billions or trillions of weights,
或者在今天的神经网络中，你可能有数十亿或万亿的权重，
And you want to find what is the value of every single one of these weights,
你想要找出每一个权重的值是多少，
that's going to result in the smallest loss as possible.
这将导致尽可能小的损失。
Now, how can you do this,
现在，你如何做到这个呢，
remember that our loss function J(W) is just a function of our weights,
记住，我们的损失函数 J(W) 只是我们权重的函数，
so for any instantiation of our weights,
所以对于任何权重的实例化，
we can compute a scalar value of you know how how erroneous would our neural network be
我们可以计算一个神经网络有多大错误的标量，
for this instantiation of our weights.
对于我们的权重实例化。
So let's try and visualize,
让我们试着想象一下，
for example, in a very simple example of a two dimensional space,
例如，在一个非常简单的二维空间中，
where we have only two weights,
我们只有两个权重，
extremely simple neural network here, very small,
这里是非常简单的神经网络，非常小，
two weight neural network,
两个权重的神经网络，
and we want to find what are the optimal weights that would train this neural network,
我们想找出训练这个神经网络的最佳权重是什么，
we can plot basically the loss,
我们可以画出损失，
how erroneous the neural network is,
神经网络的误差有多大，
for every single instantiation of these two weights, right,
对于这两个权重的每个实例化，
this is a huge space, it's an infinite space,
这是一个很大的空间，这是一个无限的空间，
but still we can try to,
但我们仍然可以尝试，
we can have a function,
我们可以有一个函数，
that evaluates at every point in this space.
在这个空间的每一点求值。
Now, what we ultimately want to do is,
现在，我们最终想要做的是，
again, we want to find which set of ws
再次，我们想要找出哪一组 ws
will give us the smallest loss possible,
将给我们带来尽可能最小的损失，
that means basically the lowest point on this landscape that you can see here,
这意味着你可以在这里看到的这个图景上的最低点，
where is the ws that bring us to that lowest point,
将我们带到最低点的 ws 在哪里，
the way that we do this is
我们做到这一点的方法是，
actually just by firstly starting at a random place,
从一个随机的地方开始，
we have no idea where to start,
我们不知道从哪里开始，
so pick a random place to start in this space
在这个空间中选择一个随机的地方开始，
and let's start there,
让我们从那里开始，
at this location, let's evaluate our neural network,
在这个位置，让我们评估一下我们的神经网络，
we can compute the loss at this specific location
我们可以计算这个特定位置的损失，
and on top of that, we can actually compute how the loss is changing,
在此基础上，我们可以计算损失是如何变化的，
we can compute the gradient of the loss,
我们可以计算损失的梯度，
because our loss function is a continuous function,
因为我们的损失函数是连续函数，
so we can actually compute derivatives of our function
所以我们可以计算函数的导数，
across the space of our weights,
通过空间中的权重，
and the gradient tells us the direction of the highest point,
梯度告诉我们最高点的方向，
so from where we stand,
所以，从我们所处的位置来看，
the gradient tells us where we should go to increase our loss,
梯度告诉我们应该去哪里增加我们的损失，
now, of course, we don't want to increase our loss,
现在，当然，我们不想增加我们的损失，
we want to decrease our loss,
我们想减少我们的损失，
so we negate our gradient
所以我们对梯度取反，
and we take a step in the opposite direction of the gradient,
我们朝着与梯度相反的方向迈出一步，
that brings us one step closer to the bottom of the landscape,
这让我们离图景的底部又近了一步，
and we just keep repeating this process over and over again,
我们只是一遍又一遍地重复这个过程，
we evaluate the neural network at this new location,
我们在这个新位置评估神经网络，
compute its gradient, and step in that new direction,
计算它的梯度，并朝着这个新方向前进，
we keep traversing this landscape until we converge to the minimum.
我们一直在穿过这个图景，直到我们汇聚到最小。
We can really summarize this algorithm,
我们可以总结这个算法，
which is known formally as gradient descent, right,
它的正式名称是梯度下降，
so gradient descent simply can be written like this,
所以梯度下降可以简单地写成这样，
we initialize all of our weights,
我们初始化所有的权重，
this can be two weights,
这可以两个权重，
like you saw in the previous example,
如你在上一个例子中看到的，
it can be billions of weights,
它可以是数十亿个权重，
like in real neural networks,
就像真正的神经网络，
we compute this gradient of the partial derivative of our loss with respect to the weights
我们计算损失的偏导数相对于权重的这个梯度，
and then we can update our weights in the opposite direction of this gradient,
然后我们可以在这个梯度的相反方向上更新我们的权重，
so essentially we just take this small amount,
所以我们只是采取这个很小的量，
small step, you can think of it,
很小的一步，你可以想象它，
which here is denoted as ,
在这里被表示为 η ，
and we refer to this small step,
我们指的是这一小步，
this is commonly referred to as what's known as the learning rate,
这通常被称为学习率，
it's like how much we want to trust that gradient
这就像我们多么相信这个梯度，
and step in the direction of that gradient,
并朝着这个梯度的方向前进，
we'll talk more about this later.
我们稍后将详细讨论这个问题。
But just to give you some sense of code,
但为了给你一些代码的感觉，
this algorithm is very well translatable to real code as well,
这个算法也可以很好地翻译成真实的代码，
for every line on the pseudo code you can see on the left,
对于你可以在左侧看到的伪代码上的每一行，
you can see corresponding real code on the right,
你都可以在右侧看到相应的真实代码，
that is runable
这些代码是可以运行的，
and directly implementable by all of you in your labs.
并且可以由你们在实验中直接实现。
But now let's take a look specifically at this term here,
但现在让我们来具体看看这个术语，
this is the gradient,
这就是梯度，
we touch very briefly on this at the visual example,
我们在可视的例子中非常简要地谈到这一点，
this explains, like I said,
这就解释了，就像我说的，
how the loss is changing as a function of the weights,
损失是如何随着权重的变化而变化的，
so as the weights move around,
所以，随着权重的移动，
will my loss increase or decrease,
我的损失是增加还是减少，
and that will tell the neural network,
这将告诉神经网络，
if it needs to move the weights in a certain direction or not.
它是否需要将权重向某个方向移动。
But I never actually told you how to compute this, right,
但我从来没有告诉过你如何计算这个，
and I think that's an extremely important part,
我认为这是一个非常重要的部分，
because if you don't know that,
因为如果你不知道这一点，
then you can't, well, you can't train your neural network,
那么你就不能训练你的神经网络，
this is a critical part of training neural networks
这是训练神经网络的关键部分，
and that process of computing this line, this gradient line is known as back propagation.
计算这条梯度线的过程被称为反向传播。
So let's do a very quick intro to back propagation
所以，让我们简要介绍一下反向传播，
and how it works.
以及它是如何工作的，
So again, let's start with the simplest neural network in existence,
再次，我们从现存的最简单的神经网络开始，
this neural network has one input, one output, and only one neuron,
这个神经网络有一个输入，一个输出，并且只有一个神经元，
this is as simple as it gets,
这就是最简单的事情，
we want to compute the gradient of our loss with respect to our weight,
我们想要计算损失相对于我们权重的梯度，
in this case, let's compute it with respect to w2, the second weight,
在这种情况下，让我们相对于 w2 ，第二个权重来计算它，
so this derivative is going to tell us
所以这个导数会告诉我们，
how much a small change in this weight will affect our loss,
权重的微小变化会对损失有多大影响，
if if a small change, if we change our weight a little bit in one direction,
如果一个小的变化，如果我们在一个方向上稍微改变一下权重，
will increase our loss or decrease our loss.
会增加我们的损失或减少我们的损失。
So to compute that, we can write out this derivative,
所以要计算它，我们可以写出这个导数，
we can start with applying the chain rule,
我们可以从应用链式规则开始，
backwards from the loss function through the output,
从损失函数到输出的反向，
specifically, what we can do is,
具体地说，我们可以做的是，
we can actually just decompose this derivative into two components,
我们可以把这个导数分解成两个分量，
the first component is the derivative of our loss with respect to our output
第一个分量是我们的损失对输出的导数，
multiplied by the derivative of our output with respect to w2, right,
乘以我们的输出对 w2 的导数，
this is just a standard instantiation of the chain rule
这只是一个标准的链式规则的实例化，
with this original derivative that we had on the left hand side.
用左侧的原始导数。
Let's suppose we wanted to compute the gradients of the weight,
让我们假设我们想要计算权重的梯度，
before that, which in this case are not w1, but w,
在此之前，在这种情况下，不是 w1 ，而是 w ，
excuse me not w2, but w1,
抱歉，不是 w2 ，而是 w1 ，
well, all we do is replace w2 with w1
我们所做的就是用 w1 替换 w2 ，
and that chain rule still holds, right,
链式法则仍然有效，
that same equation holds,
同样的方程成立，
but now you can see on the red component,
但现在你可以在红色部分看到，
that last component of the chain rule,
链式规则的最后一个部分，
we have to once again recursively apply one more chain rule,
我们必须再次递归地应用另一个链式规则，
because that's again another derivative that we can't directly evaluate,
因为这又是另一个我们不能直接求值的导数，
we can expand that once more with another instantiation of the chain rule,
我们可以用链式规则的另一个实例化再次扩展，
and now all of these components,
现在所有这些组件，
we can directly propagate these gradients through the hidden units, right,
都可以通过神经网络中的隐藏单元直接传播这些梯度，
in our neural network,
在我们的神经网络中，
all the way back to the weight that're interested in in this example, right,
一直回到这个例子中感兴趣的权重，
so we first computed the derivative with respect to w2,
所以我们首先计算对 w2 的导数，
then we can back propagate that and use that information,
然后我们可以反向传播这些信息，并使用这些信息，
also with w1,
也对于 w1 ，
that's why we really call it back propagation,
这就是为什么我们称之为反向传播，
because this process occurs from the output all the way back to the input.
因为这个过程发生从输出一直到输入。
Now, we repeat this process essentially many, many times
现在，我们在训练过程中重复这个过程很多次，
over the course of training by propagating these gradients over and over again through the network,
通过网络一遍又一遍地传播这些梯度，
all the way from the output to the inputs to determine for every single weight, answering this question,
从输出到输入来确定每个单一权重，回答这个问题，
which is how much does a small change in these weights affect our loss function,
即这些权重的微小变化对我们的损失函数的影响有多大，
if it increases it or decreases,
它是增加或减少，
and how we can use that to improve the loss ultimately,
以及我们如何利用它来最终改善损失，
because that's our final goal in this class.
因为这是我们这门课的最终目标。
So that's the back propagation algorithm,
这就是反向传播算法，
that's, that's the core of training neural networks,
那是训练神经网络的核心，
in theory, it's very simple,
理论上，这很简单，
it's, it's really just an instantiation of the chain rule,
这只是链条规则的实例化，
but let's touch on some insights,
但让我们来谈谈一些见解，
that make training neural networks actually extremely complicated in practice,
使训练神经网络在实践中变得极其复杂，
even though the algorithm of back propagation is simple
尽管反向传播的算法很简单，
and, you know, many decades old,
而且几十年时间，
in practice though, optimization of neural networks looks something like this,
然而，在实践中，神经网络的优化看起来就像这样，
it looks nothing like that picture that I showed you before,
它看起来一点也不像我之前给你看的那张图片，
there are ways that we can visualize very large, deep neural networks,
有很多方法可以让我们看到非常大、很深的神经网络，
and you can think of the landscape of these models looking like something like this,
你可以想象这些模型的图景是这样的，
this is an illustration from a paper that came out several years ago,
这是几年前发表的一篇论文中的一个插图，
where they tried to actually visualize the landscape of very, very deep neural networks,
他们试图可视化非常、非常深的神经网络的图景，
and that's what this landscape actually looks like,
这就是这个图景的真实面貌，
that's what you're trying to deal with and find the minimum in this space,
这就是你试图处理的，在这个空间中找到最小的，
and you can imagine the challenges that come with that,
你可以想象随之而来的挑战，
to cover the challenges,
为了涵盖这些挑战，
let's first think of and recall that update equation defined in gradient descent, right.
让我们首先考虑并回想一下在梯度下降中定义的更新方程。
So, I didn't talk too much about this parameter ,
所以我没有太多地谈论这个参数 η ，
but now let's spend a bit of time thinking about this,
但是现在让我们花一点时间来思考这个，
this is called the learning rate,
这就是所谓的学习率，
like we saw before,
就像我们之前看到的那样，
it determines basically how big of a step we need to take in the direction of our gradient
它决定了我们需要在梯度方向上迈出多大的一步，
and every single iteration of back propagation,
以及反向传播的每一次迭代，
in practice, even setting the learning rate can be very challenging,
在实践中，即使是设定学习速度也可能是非常具有挑战性的，
you as, you as the designer of the neural network,
你作为神经网络的设计者，
have to set this value, this learning rate
必须设置这个值，这个学习率，
and how do you pick this value, right,
如何选择这个值，
so that can actually be quite difficult,
这可能是相当困难的，
it has really large consequences when building a neural network,
在构建神经网络时，它会产生非常大的影响，
So, for example, if we set the learning rate too low,
所以，比如，如果我们把学习率设定得太低，
then we learn very slowly,
然后我们学得很慢，
so let's assume we start on the right hand side here,
我们假设我们从右手边开始，
at that initial guess,
在最初的猜测中，
if our learning rate is not large enough,
如果我们的学习率不够大，
not only do we converge slowly,
我们不仅收敛得很慢，
we actually don't even converge to the global minimum,
我们甚至不会收敛到全局最小值，
because we kind of get stuck in a local minimum,
因为我们有点陷入局部最小值，
now, what if we set our learning rate too high, right,
现在，如果我们把我们的学习率设定得太高，
What can actually happen is,
可能发生的情况是，
we overshoot and we can actually start to diverge from the solution,
我们超调了，我们可能开始偏离解决方案，
the gradients can actually explode,
这些渐变可能会爆炸，
very bad things happen,
非常糟糕的事情发生，
and then the neural network doesn't trade,
然后神经网络就不交易了，
so that's also not good,
所以这也不是什么好事，
in reality, there's a very happy medium between setting it too small, setting it too large,
实际上，在把它设置得太小，设置得太大，之间有一个非常好的中间选择，
where you set it, just large enough to kind of overshoot some of these local minima,
你设置的地方，大到足以超过某些局部极小值之间，
put you into a reasonable part of the search space,
把你放在搜索空间的合理部分，
where then you can actually converge on the solutions that you care most about.
在那里你可以真正收敛到你最关心的解决方案上。
But, actually, how do you set these learning rates in practice,
但是，实际上，你是如何在实践中设定这些学习率的，
how do you pick what is the ideal learning rate.
你如何选择理想的学习率是多少。
One option, and this is actually a very common option in practice,
一种选择，实际上这在实践中是非常常见的选择，
is to simply try out a bunch of learning rates
就是简单地尝试一系列学习率，
and see what works the best,
看看哪种效果最好，所以试一试，比方说，一个由不同学习率组成的整个网格，你知道，训练所有这些神经网络，看看哪一个工作得最好。
so try out, let's say, a whole grid of different learning rates
所以试一试，比方说，一个由不同学习率组成的整个网格，
and, you know, train all of these neural networks,
训练所有这些神经网络，
see which one works the best.
看看哪一个工作得最好。
But I think we can do something a lot smarter, right,
但我觉得我们可以做更聪明的事，
so what are some more intelligent ways that we could do this,
那么，我们有哪些更聪明的方法可以做到这一点，
instead of exhaustively trying out a whole bunch of different learning rates,
而不是详尽地尝试一大堆不同的学习率，
can we design a learning rate algorithm
我们能不能设计一种学习率算法
that actually adapts to our neural network and adapts to its landscape,
来适应我们的神经网络，并适应它的图景，
so that it's a bit more intelligent than that previous idea.
这样它就比以前的想法更智能。
So this really ultimately means that,
所以，这实际上最终意味着，
the learning rate, the speed at which the algorithm is trusting the gradients that it sees
学习率，算法信任梯度的速度
is going to depend on how large the gradient is in that location
将取决于该位置的梯度有多大，
and how fast we're learning,
以及我们学习的速度有多快，
how many other options, and sorry, and many other options,
有多少其他选择，抱歉，许多其他选择，
that we might have as part of training in neural networks, right,
作为神经网络训练的一部分，
so it's not only how quickly we're learning,
所以，不仅是我们学习的速度有多快，
you may judge in on many different factors in the learning landscape.
你还可以根据学习图景中的许多不同因素进行判断。
In fact, we've all been these different algorithms, that I'm talking about,
事实上，我们都是我所说的这些不同的算法，
these adaptive learning rate algorithms have been very widely studied in practice,
这些自适应学习率算法在实践中得到了非常广泛的研究，
there is a very thriving community, in the deep learning research community,
在深度学习研究社区中，有一个非常蓬勃发展的社区，
that focuses on developing and designing new algorithms for learning rate adaptation
专注于开发和设计学习率自适应新的算法，
and faster optimization of large neural networks like these,
更快地优化像这样的大型神经网络，
and during your labs,
在你的实验中，
you'll actually get the opportunity to not only try out a lot of these different adaptive algorithms,
你不仅有机会尝试许多不同的自适应算法，
which you can see here,
你可以在这里看到的，
but also try to uncover what are kind of the patterns and benefits of one versus the other,
但也试图揭示一种模式和另一种模式的好处，
and that's going to be something that I think you'll find very insightful
我认为这将是非常有洞察力的东西，
as part of your labs.
作为你们实验的一部分。
So another key component of your labs that you'll see is,
所以，你们将看到的实验的另一个关键部分是，
how you can actually put all of this information that we've covered today into a single picture that looks roughly something like this,
如何将我们今天介绍的所有这些信息实际放入一张大致类似于下面的图片中，
which defines your model at the first, at the top here,
这张图片首先定义了你的模型，在这里的顶部，
that's where you define your model,
这是你定义模型的地方，
where you talked about this in the beginning part of the lecture.
你在课程的开头部分谈到了这一点。
For every piece in your model,
对于模型中的每一部分，
you're now going to need to define this optimizer,
你现在都需要定义这个优化器，
which we've just talked about,
我们刚刚谈到了这一点，
this optimizer is defined together with a learning rate, right,
这个优化器是和学习率一起定义的，
how quickly you want to optimize your loss landscape
你想要以多快的速度优化你的损失图景，
and over many loops, you're going to pass over all of the examples in your data set,
经过许多循环，你将通过你数据集中的所有例子，
and observe essentially how to improve your network, that's the gradient,
从本质上观察如何改善你的神经网络，这就是梯度，
and then actually improves the network in those directions,
然后在这些方向上改善网络，
and keep doing that over and over and over again,
一遍又一遍地这样做，
until eventually your neural network converges to some sort of solution.
直到你的神经网络最终收敛到某种解决方案。
So I want to very quickly, briefly,
所以，我想非常简短地，
in the remaining time that we have,
在剩下的时间里，
continue to talk about tips for training these neural networks in practice
继续谈论训练这些神经网络的实践中的技巧，
and focus on this very powerful idea
并专注于这个非常强大的想法，
of batching your data into what are called mini-batches of of smaller pieces of data.
将你的数据批量处理成所谓的小批量较小的数据片段。
To do this, let's revisit that gradient descent algorithm, right,
为此，让我们重温梯度下降算法，
so here, this gradient that we talked about before is
所以在这里，我们之前讨论的这个梯度，
actually extraordinarily computationally expensive to compute,
计算起来非常昂贵，
because it's computed as a summation across all of the pieces in your data set,
因为它是通过数据集中所有部分的总和来计算的，
and in most real life or real world problems,
在大多数现实生活或现实世界的问题中，
you know, it's simply not feasible to compute a gradient over your entire data set,
在你的整个数据集上计算梯度是不可行的，
data sets are just too large these days.
如今的数据集实在太大了。
So you know there are some alternatives, right,
所以你知道还有其他选择，
what are the alternatives,
还有其他选择吗，
instead of computing the derivative or the gradients across your entire data set,
不是计算整个数据集的导数或梯度，
what if you instead computed the gradient over just a single example in your dataas set,
而是只计算数据集中的单个示例的梯度，
just one example,
就一个例子，
well, of course this, this estimate of your gradient is going to be exactly that,
当然，这个，对你的梯度的估计，就是这样，
it's an estimate, it's going to be very noisy,
这是一个估计，它将是非常嘈杂的，
it may roughly reflect the trends of your entire data set,
它可能粗略地反映了你整个数据集的趋势，
but because it's a very, it's only one example in fact of your entire data set,
但因为它是一个非常，它只是你整个数据集的一个例子，
it may be very noisy.
它可能会非常嘈杂。
Well, the advantage of this though is that,
这样做的好处是，
it's much faster to compute obviously the gradient over a single example,
在一个例子中，计算梯度明显要快得多，
because it's one example,
因为这是一个例子，
so computationally this has huge advantages,
所以从计算上来说，这有很大的优势，
but the downside is that it's extremely stochastic,
但缺点是它是非常随机的，
that's the reason why this algorithm is not called gradient descent,
这就是为什么这种算法不叫梯度下降的原因，
it's called stochastic gradient descent now.
这现在被称为随机梯度下降。
Now, what's the middle ground, right,
现在，中间立场是什么，
instead of computing it with respect to one example in your data set,
与其针对数据集中的一个示例计算它，
what if we computed what's called a mini-batch of examples,
不如我们计算所谓的一小批示例，
a small batch of examples that we can compute the gradients over,
一小批我们可以计算梯度的例子，
and when we take these gradients,
当我们计算这些梯度时，
they're still computationally efficient to compute,
它们的计算效率仍然很高，
because it's a mini-batch, it's not too large,
因为它是一个小批量，不是太大，
maybe we're talking on the order of tens or hundreds of examples in our dataset,
也许我们谈论的是我们数据集中数十或数百个例子的数量级，
but, more importantly,
但是，更重要的是，
because we've expanded from a single example to maybe a hundred examples,
因为我们已经从一个例子扩展到可能一百个例子，
the stochasticity is significantly reduced
随机性显著降低，
and the accuracy of our gradient is much improved.
我们的梯度的精度大大提高。
So normally we're thinking of batch sizes, mini-batch sizes,
所以通常我们考虑的是批次大小，小型批次大小，
roughly on the order of a hundred data points, tens or hundreds of data points,
大约 100 个数据点，数十个或数百个数据点，
this is much faster obviously to compute than gradient descent
这显然比梯度下降的计算速度快得多，
and much more accurate to compute compared to stochastic gradient descent,
比随机梯度下降的计算精度高得多，
which is that single single point example.
后者是单点的例子。
So this increase in gradient accuracy allows us
所以，梯度精度的提高使我们
to essentially converge to our solution much quicker,
能够更快地收敛到我们的解，
than it could have been possible in practice due to gradient descent limitations,
而不是由于梯度下降的限制而在实践中可能实现的，
it also means that we can increase our learning rate,
这也意味着我们可以提高我们的学习率，
because we can trust each of those gradients much more efficiently, right,
因为我们可以更有效地信任每个梯度，
we're now averaging over a batch,
我们现在是一批的平均数，
it's going to be much more accurate than the stochastic version,
它将比随机版本精确得多，
so we can increase that learning rate
所以我们可以提高学习率，
and actually learn faster as well.
也可以学得更快。
This allows us to also massively parallelize this entire algorithm and computation, right,
这使得我们还可以大规模并行化整个算法和计算，
we can split up batches onto separate workers
我们可以把批次分成不同的工作者，
and achieve even more significant speedups of this entire problem using GPUs.
并使用 GPU 实现整个问题更显著的加速。
The last topic that I very, very briefly want to cover in today's lecture is
在今天的演讲中，我非常、非常简短地想要讨论的最后一个话题是，
this topic of overfitting, right,
这个话题就是过度拟合，
when we're optimizing a neural network with stochastic gradient descent,
当我们使用随机梯度下降来优化神经网络的时候，
we have this challenge of what's called overfitting,
我们遇到了这个挑战，所谓的过拟合，
overfitting looks like this roughly, right,
过拟合看起来大致这样，
so on the left hand side,
所以在左手边，
we want to build a neural network,
我们想要建立一个神经网络，
or let's say, in general, we want to build a machine learning model,
或者说，总的来说，我们想要建立一个机器学习模型，
that can accurately describe some patterns in our data,
它可以准确地描述我们数据中的一些模式，
but remember, ultimately we don't want to describe the patterns in our training data,
但请记住，最终我们不想描述我们的训练数据中的模式，
ideally, we want to define the patterns in our test data,
理想情况下，我们希望定义测试数据中的模式，
of course, we don't observe test data, we only observe training data,
当然，我们不观察测试数据，我们只观察训练数据，
so we have this challenge of extracting patterns from training data
所以，我们面临着这个挑战，从训练数据中提取模式，
and hoping that they generalize to our test data.
并希望它们推广到我们的测试数据。
So said in one different way,
所以，换一种不同的说法，
we want to build models that can learn representations from our training data,
我们希望构建能够从我们的训练数据中学习表示法的模型，
that can still generalize,
这些模型仍然可以泛化，
even when we show them brand new unseen pieces of test data.
即使我们向它们展示全新的、没见过的测试数据片段。
So assume that you want to build a line,
假设你想构建一条直线，
that can describe or find the patterns in these points, that you can see on the slide,
它可以描述或找到幻灯片上这些点的模式，
if you have a very simple neural network,
如果你有一个非常简单的神经网络，
which is just a single line, straight line.
这只是一条直线。
You can describe this data suboptimally, right,
你可以以次优的方式描述这个数据，
because the data here is non-linear,
因为这里的数据是非线性的，
you're not going to accurately capture all of the nuances and subtleties in this data set,
你不会准确地捕捉到这个数据集中的所有细微差别和微妙之处，
that's on the left hand side,
这在左手边，
if you move to the right hand side,
如果你移到右手边，
you can see a much more complicated model,
你可以看到一个更复杂的模型，
but here you're actually over expressive, you're too expressive,
但这里你表达得太多了，你太有表现力了，
and you're capturing kind of the nuances, the spurious nuances in your training data,
你捕捉到了训练数据中的某种细微差别，虚假的细微差别，
that are actually not representative of your test data.
实际上并不能表示你的测试数据。
Ideally you want to end up with the model in the middle,
理想情况下，你希望模型位于中间，
which is basically the middle ground, right,
这就是中间地带，
it's not too complex and it's not too simple,
这不是太复杂，也不是太简单，
it still gives you what you want to perform well
它仍然会给你你想要的表现良好的东西，
and even when you give it brand new data.
即使你给了它全新的数据。
So, to address this problem,
所以，为了解决这个问题，
let's briefly talk about what's called regularization,
让我们简要地谈谈所谓的正则化，
regularization is a technique,
正则化是一种技术，
that you can introduce to your training pipeline
你可以将其引入到训练管道中，
to discourage complex models from being learned.
以阻止学习复杂的模型。
Now, as we've seen before,
现在，正如我们之前看到的，
this is really critical,
这一点非常关键，
because neural networks are extremely large models,
因为神经网络是非常大的模型，
they are extremely prone to overfitting,
它们非常容易过拟合，
so regularization and having techniques for regularization has extreme implications towards the success of neural networks
所以正则化和拥有正则化技术对神经网络的成功有着极端的影响，
and having them generalize beyond training data
让它们超越训练数据，
far into our testing domain.
推广到我们的测试领域。
The most popular technique for regularization in deep learning is called dropout,
深度学习中最流行的正则化技术称为 dropout ，
and the idea of dropout is is actually very simple,
dropout 的想法其实很简单，
let's revisit it by drawing this picture of deep neural networks,
让我们通过绘制深度神经网络的图片来重温它，
that we saw earlier in today's lecture,
我们在今天的讲座前面看到的，
in dropout, during training,
在 dropout ，在训练期间，
we essentially randomly select some subset of the neurons in this neural network,
我们随机选择这个神经网络中的一些神经元子集，
and we try to tune them out with some random probabilities,
我们试着用一些随机的概率把他们排除在外，
so, for example, we can select this subset of of neurons,
例如，我们可以选择这部分神经元，
we can randomly select them with a probability of 50%
我们可以以 50% 的概率随机选择它们，
and with that probability,
使用这个概率，
we randomly turn them off or on on different iterations of our training.
我们在训练的不同迭代中随机关闭或打开它们。
So this is essentially forcing the neural network to learn,
所以，这本质上是迫使神经网络学习，
you can think of an ensemble of different models,
你可以想到一个由不同模型组成的整体，
on every iteration,
在每次迭代中，
it's going to be exposed to kind of a different model internally
它将在迭代不同的模型，
than the one it had on the last iteration,
比起它在上一次迭代中，
so it has to learn how to build internal pathways to process the same information,
所以，它必须学习如何建立内部路径来处理相同的信息，
and it can't rely on information that it learned on previous iterations,
而且它不能依赖从以前的迭代中学到的信息，
so it forces it to kind of capture some deeper meaning within the pathways of the neural network,
它迫使它在某种程度上捕捉到神经网络路径中的一些更深层次的含义，
and this can be extremely powerful,
这可能是非常强大的，
because number one, it lowers the capacity of the neural network significantly,
因为第一，它显著降低了神经网络的容量，
you're lowering it by roughly 50% in this example,
在本例中，您将它降低了大约 50% ，
but also because it makes them easier to train,
这也是因为它使它们更容易训练，
because the number of weights that have gradients in this case is also reduced,
因为在这种情况下，具有梯度的权重的数量也减少了，
so it's actually much faster to train them as well.
所以训练它们也要快得多。
Now like I mentioned,
现在就像我提到的，
on every iteration we randomly dropout a different set of neurons, right,
在每一次迭代中，我们随机 dropout 一组不同的神经元，
and that helps the data generalize better.
这有助于更好地概括数据。
And the second regularization techniques,
第二种正则化技术，
which is actually a very broad regularization techniques far beyond neural networks
是一种远远超出神经网络的非常广泛的正则化技术，
is simply called early stopping.
简单地称为提前停止。
Now we know the definition of overfitting is simply
我们知道过拟合的定义是，
when our model starts to represent basically the training data more than the testing data,
当我们的模型开始更多地代表训练数据而不是测试数据时，
that's really what overfitting comes down to at its core,
这确实是过度适应的核心所在，
if we set aside some of the training data to use separately,
如果我们把一些训练数据放在一边单独使用，
that we don't train on it,
我们没有在上面训练，
we can use kind of a testing data set, synthetic testing data set,
我们可以使用某种测试数据集，合成测试数据集，
in some ways, we can monitor how our network is learning on this unseen portion of data,
在某些方面，我们可以监控我们的网络如何学习这部分没看见的数据，
so for example, we can over the course of training,
例如，我们可以在整个训练过程中，
we can basically plot the performance of our network,
我们可以绘制出网络的性能，
on both the training set as well as our held out test set
在训练集和我们的坚持测试集上，
and as the network is trained,
随着网络的训练，
we're going to see that first of all these both decrease,
我们将首先看到这两个参数都有所下降，
but there's going to be a point,
但总有一天，
where the loss plateaus and starts to increase,
损失会停滞不前并开始增加，
the training loss will actually start to increase,
训练损失开始增加，
this is exactly the point where you start to overfit,
这正是你开始过拟合的时候，
because now you're starting to have,
因为现在你开始有，
sorry, that was the test loss,
抱歉，这是测试损失，
the test loss actually starts to increase,
测试损失实际上开始增加，
because now you're starting to overfit on your training data,
因为现在你开始过拟合你的训练数据，
this pattern basically continues for the rest of training,
这种模式会在接下来的训练中持续下去，
and this is the point that I want you to focus on,
这就是我希望你们关注的一点，
this middlepoint is where we need to stop training,
这个中间点是我们需要停止训练的地方，
because after this point,
因为在这一点之后，
assuming that this test set is a valid representation of the true test set,
假设该测试集是真实测试集的有效表示，
this is the place where the accuracy of the model will only get worse,
这是模型的准确性只会变差的地方，
so this is where we would want to early stop our model
所以这就是我们想要提前停止我们的模式，
and regularize the performance.
并使性能正规化的地方。
And we can see that,
我们可以看到，
stopping anytime before this point is also not good,
在这一点之前的任何时候停止也是不好的，
we're going to produce an underfit model,
我们将生产一个不适合的模型，
where we could have had a better model on the test data,
在这个模型中，我们可以根据测试数据得到更好的模型，
but it's this trade off, right,
但这是一种权衡，
you can't stop too late, and you can't stop too early as well.
你不能停得太晚，也不能停得太早。
So I'll conclude this lecture by just summarizing these three key points,
所以我将通过总结这三个要点来结束这节课，
that we've covered in today's lecture so far.
我们在今天的课上讲到的。
So we first covered these fundamental building blocks of all neural networks,
所以我们首先介绍了所有神经网络的这些基本组成部分，
which is the single neuron, the perceptron,
这就是单个神经元，感知器，
we've built these up into larger neural layers,
我们已经将它们构建成更大的神经层，
and then from their neural networks and deep neural networks,
然后从它们的神经网络和深度神经网络中，
we've learned how we can train these,
我们学习了如何训练它们，
apply them to data sets back,
将它们应用到数据集，
propagate through them,
通过它们进行传播，
and we've seen some trips, tips and tricks for optimizing these systems end to end.
我们已经看到了一些端到端优化这些系统的技巧。
In the next lecture,
在下一节课中，
we'll hear from Ava on deep sequence modeling using RNNs,
我们将听到 Ava 关于使用 RNN 深度序列建模，
and specifically this very exciting new type of model
特别是这种非常令人兴奋的新型模型，
called the transformer architecture and attention mechanisms,
称为转换器体系结构和注意机制，
so maybe let's resume the class in about five minutes
所以，大约五分钟后我们再继续上课，
after we have a chance to swap speakers,
也许在我们有机会交换演讲者之后，
and thank you so much for all of your attention.
非常感谢大家的关注。